Please listen to this part really carefully.
请认真听这部分。
If you're good at organizing your thoughts whether in your mind or on paper it's going to be a lot easier
如果你善于组织你的想法，无论是在脑海中还是在纸上，都会容易得多
for you to speak clearly if you're trying very hard to think about what to say and how to say it.
如果您非常努力地思考该说什么以及如何说，那么您就可以说清楚。
And you know the pronunciation and all that stuff it's going to be really hard for you to express yourself
而且你知道发音和所有这些东西，你很难表达自己
clearly.
清楚地。
You're probably going to make a lot more mistakes because you're going to exceed your bandwidth your
你可能会犯更多的错误，因为你会超出你的带宽
ability to focus on everything.
专注于一切的能力。
But if you're able to organize your thoughts at the very least on paper everything gets a lot easier
但是，如果您至少能够在纸上组织您的想法，那么一切都会变得容易得多
when you're doing a presentation.
当你在做演示时。
The outline is so important.
大纲太重要了。
If if you make a clear outline and you really get the ideas you really feel the ideas you have your
如果你制定了一个清晰的大纲并且你真的得到了你的想法你真的感觉到你有你的想法
mind around the ideas in the outline.
围绕大纲中的想法。
All you have to do is go through it.
你所要做的就是经历它。
One two three four five.
一二三四五。
It's easy.
这很简单。
So in this part of the lesson we're going to talk about how to make an outline.
因此，在本课的这一部分，我们将讨论如何制作大纲。
We're going to make one together and then we're going to actually after this do a presentation I'm going
我们将一起制作一个，然后我们将在此之后做一个演示，我要去
to do a presentation based on the outline just to be clear the outline is the basic structure.
根据大纲做一个演示只是为了明确大纲是基本结构。
The a done be done done see that.
完成了就完成了。
That tells you what to say next and then and then and then and then it's nothing more than that.
这告诉你接下来要说什么，然后，然后，然后，仅此而已。
If you write down all of the words you want to say in your outline it's not really an outline anymore.
如果你在大纲中写下所有你想说的话，那它就不再是真正的大纲了。
It's more like a script and it's going to be really hard to read through and you're going to get confused.
它更像是一个脚本，很难阅读，你会感到困惑。
It's truly going to be a mess.
真的会一团糟。
So keep it really simple.
所以保持非常简单。
I try to keep outlines to just a couple words really like a skeleton a basic basic structure that reminds
我尽量只保留几个单词的轮廓，就像骨架一样，一个基本的基本结构，让人想起
me of what to talk about next.
我接下来要谈什么。
Then I let the words come out of my mouth as they would like to pretty much.
然后我让这些话从我嘴里说出来，就像他们非常喜欢的那样。
I mean I try to.
我的意思是我尝试。
I try to say things clearly but I'm not too focused on what what should I talk about next.
我试着把事情说清楚，但我不太专注于接下来我应该说什么。
And that makes things a lot easier.
这让事情变得容易多了。
So keep it simple.
所以保持简单。
And that will help you a lot too.
这也会对你有很大帮助。
Let's actually do it.
让我们实际去做吧。
Our topic will be the value of travel the value of travel.
我们的主题将是旅行的价值旅行的价值。
Yes that will be our topic.
是的，这将是我们的主题。
That's more than just by the way travel itself.
这不仅仅是旅行本身的方式。
But why is travel something that's actually important.
但是为什么旅行实际上很重要。
That's what I want to talk about.
这就是我想谈的。
Now what's my hook kind of hook do I want to use.
现在我想用什么钩子。
Let's let's just go with something very basic.
让我们只做一些非常基本的事情。
By the way go with if I haven't explained that before I often say that go with means choose let's go
顺便说一句 go with 如果我没有解释之前我经常说 go with 意味着选择 let's go
with something very basic very simple very basic.
用一些非常基本的东西非常简单非常基本。
Let's just ask for a show of hands for our hook.
让我们要求为我们的钩子举手。
Keep it simple.
把事情简单化。
OK.
好的。
And I'm gonna write down the hook because it's so short.
我要写下钩子，因为它太短了。
Who here.
谁来了。
Who here sees travel as as more than just a vacation.
谁在这里认为旅行不仅仅是一个假期。
Hands up.
举手。
OK.
好的。
So that's one of the hooks that we talked about earlier.
这就是我们之前谈到的钩子之一。
Just one of the hooks hands up one the interaction one of course we could do a rhetorical question if
只是其中一个钩子举起一个互动当然我们可以做一个反问如果
we wanted to.
我们想要。
Have you ever been on a trip and had a really profound experience.
你有没有去过一次旅行并且有过非常深刻的经历。
I'd like you to think about that experience as I begin my presentation that one time.
我希望你在我开始我的演讲时考虑一下那次经历。
OK.
好的。
So I'm going to use this one just because it's so simple and I am going to write it down only because
所以我要使用这个只是因为它很简单而且我要写我t下来只是因为
it's so short.
太短了。
Normally as long as you have the basic idea of it in your mind that is totally fine.
通常，只要您对它有基本的想法，那是完全可以的。
Now how about the introduction.
现在介绍如何。
What about the introduction.
介绍呢。
Do we always need an introduction.
我们总是需要介绍吗？
Well I like to do something really simple.
好吧，我喜欢做一些非常简单的事情。
I usually just say today today I would or I'd like to share with you.
我通常只是说今天今天我愿意或我想与你分享。
I usually say something like this today I'd like to share with you.
我通常会说这样的话，今天我想和你分享。
It's just a way to say hey this is my topic after my hook so I'll give my hook first and then I'll give
这只是一种表达方式，嘿，这是我的钩子之后的话题，所以我会先给出我的钩子，然后我会给出
my basic basic introduction doesn't have to be anything too long or too serious pretty simple.
我的基本基本介绍不必太长或太严肃，非常简单。
Then we get into the actual outline itself.
然后我们进入实际的轮廓本身。
So let's break down and build together the outline of our presentation on the value of travel.
因此，让我们分解并共同构建我们关于旅行价值的演示文稿的大纲。
My basic structure for doing an outline is a there's going to be a point here then.
我做大纲的基本结构是这里有一个要点。
Example example or detailed detail B.
示例或详细信息 B.
The main point here.
重点在这里。
Second main point example here.
这里的第二个要点示例。
Detail here could be an example or a specific detail about it depending on the topic.
此处的详细信息可能是示例或有关它的特定详细信息，具体取决于主题。
Then sometimes not always see main point.
然后有时并不总是看到要点。
Example example for example detail or whatever.
示例示例，例如详细信息或其他任何内容。
And then so comma and I'll say one last thing and there are many ways to do that.
然后是逗号，我会说最后一件事，有很多方法可以做到这一点。
You don't have to use so I generally like to use so when I'm doing a presentation.
你不必使用所以我通常喜欢在我做演示时使用so。
So this is our basic our basic structure and of course here we have our of course our basic hook and
所以这是我们的基本我们的基本结构，当然这里我们当然有我们的基本钩子和
our intro so hook Intro A B C so at the very end a exposure to new ideas exposure to new ideas.
我们的介绍如此挂钩 Intro A B C 所以最后是接触新想法 接触新想法。
All right.
好的。
That's a good one.
这是一个很好的。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
Example number one.
示例一。
Oh OK.
哦好的。
Trip to India then I'm gonna write shock here to remind myself to talk about the sort of culture shock
去印度旅行，然后我会在这里写休克来提醒自己谈论那种文化冲击
of going to India for the first time very different than America.
第一次去印度和美国很不一样。
Good experience.
好的经历。
Next let's see.
接下来让我们看看。
Eating traditions eating traditions.
吃传统吃传统。
OK I'm just gonna write eating traditions because I know what I want to share when I talk about eating
好的，我只是要写饮食传统，因为当我谈论饮食时，我知道我想分享什么
traditions.
传统。
I have something in my head but this helps me remember what I'm going to talk about.
我脑子里有些东西，但这有助于我记住我要谈论的内容。
I'm going to talk about how on my many trips I like to sample local food especially street food because
我要谈谈在我的许多旅行中，我喜欢品尝当地美食，尤其是街头美食，因为
then I feel like I can get a deep feeling for the history of each place.
然后我觉得我可以对每个地方的历史有很深的感受。
I'm going to talk about that but I'm just going to use eating traditions to help me remember what I'm
我要谈谈这个，但我只是要利用饮食传统来帮助我记住我是什么
going to talk about.
要去谈谈。
All right.
好的。
So this is part A the main idea why is travel valuable.
所以这是 A 部分的主要思想，为什么旅行很有价值。
Well because you get exposure that means you get to see new ideas and that makes you reflect and think
好吧，因为你得到了曝光，这意味着你可以看到新的想法，这会让你反思和思考
about who you are where you come from be.
关于你是谁，你来自哪里。
Get get.
得到得到。
Oh no let's not use get.
哦，不，我们不要使用 get。
I want to make it even shorter.
我想让它更短。
A break from routine.
打破常规。
So for this one I'm going to talk about why it's so important to not do the same thing every day and
所以对于这个我要谈谈为什么不每天都做同样的事情如此重要
how travel can really break you out of doing the same thing and give you a lot of new fresh ideas and
旅行如何真正让你摆脱做同样的事情并给你很多新的想法和
improve the quality of of your life.
提高您的生活质量。
Explore inner self who you are on the inside.
探索你内在的内在自我。
And I'm going to give a detail on that.
我将对此进行详细说明。
The next one I want to really make it pretty short.
下一个我真的想把它做得很短。
I'm gonna write normal life fresh eyes and then I'm going to talk about how when you come back from
我会用新鲜的眼光写下正常的生活然后我会谈谈你回来后的样子
traveling for maybe two weeks or even a month when you come back to your own life you can appreciate
旅行可能两周甚至一个月n 你回到你自己的生活，你可以欣赏
it in a totally new way.
它以一种全新的方式。
You realize that it is maybe interesting you can see the value in it whereas before when you left you
您意识到这可能很有趣，您可以看到其中的价值，而在您离开之前
are sick and tired and everything was dumb and boring.
又病又累，一切都愚蠢而无聊。
I want to talk about that now see let's do global network again.
我现在想谈谈这个，让我们再做一次全球网络。
We're talking about the value of travel.
我们正在谈论旅行的价值。
We have three main ideas one is about exposing yourself to new ideas and new ways of life and the value
我们有三个主要的想法一个是关于让自己接触新的想法和新的生活方式和价值
of that be.
那是。
Point being number two is about breaking away out of your normal routine.
第二点是要摆脱你的日常工作。
Why that's so important to do and then see is about your Global Network who you know around the world.
为什么这样做如此重要，然后查看是关于您在世界各地认识的全球网络。
And I'm gonna give an example.
我要举个例子。
Staying in Japan I know what that means.
留在日本我知道那意味着什么。
I have a little story for that.
我有一个小故事。
Your outline is for you.
你的大纲是给你的。
You don't have to show it to everybody else.
你不必向其他人展示它。
I'm showing it to you because I'm showing you the process for making it.
我向你展示它是因为我向你展示了制作它的过程。
It's so easy but it really it's for me.
这很容易，但它真的适合我。
It reminds me of the story I want to talk about my example of staying in Japan.
这让我想起了我想谈谈我留在日本的例子的故事。
Then I'm going to say unexpected adventures unexpected adventures and then I'm going to talk about how
然后我会说意外的冒险意外的冒险然后我会谈谈如何
when I meet people when I am traveling I think maybe oh I'm going to go to this place I'm going to visit
当我在旅行时遇到人 我想也许哦 我要去这个地方 我要去参观
this this and this.
这个这个这个。
But I end up meeting people and we do things together and that makes the experience much more interesting.
但我最终会遇到一些人，我们一起做事，这让体验变得更加有趣。
I have a deeper experience and a deeper appreciation for the place I'm visiting because I've met people
我对我正在访问的地方有更深的体验和更深的欣赏，因为我遇到了人
and my my growing network is making my travels more valuable all the time.
我不断增长的网络使我的旅行一直更有价值。
So next time you're planning that's my beginning I'm gonna say planning a trip just helps me remember.
所以下次你计划那是我的开始，我会说计划一次旅行只是帮助我记住。
All right.
好的。
So let's just review this a exposure to new ideas.
因此，让我们回顾一下这种对新想法的接触。
Talk about my trip to India and the culture shock me that I'm going to talk about eating traditions.
谈谈我的印度之旅和文化让我震惊，我要谈谈饮食传统。
OK so those are new things that are adding value b get away from my normal life.
好的，所以这些是增加价值的新事物 b 远离我的正常生活。
Get out of my routine and learn more about myself but also when I come back see my own life with fresh
走出我的日常生活，更多地了解自己
eyes see my network around the world and stay with my friend in Japan for example and unexpected adventures
眼睛看到我在世界各地的网络，例如和我在日本的朋友呆在一起，还有意想不到的冒险
valuable experiences that I never planned to have.
我从未计划过的宝贵经验。
So next time you plan or you're planning a trip I'm going to talk about how if you stay in a hotel by
所以下次你计划或计划旅行时，我会谈谈如果你住在酒店
yourself it's probably not good.
自己可能不太好。
So next time you're planning a trip don't stay in a five star resort a resort is a resort is a very
所以下次你计划旅行时不要住在五星级度假村
nice place.
好地方。
Of course it's good to do that.
当然，这样做很好。
If you really just want to relax.
如果你真的只是想放松一下。
But if you really want to meet people maybe go out and explore the local area.
但如果你真的想认识人，可以出去探索当地。
All right.
好的。
So I've got my ideas down I'm going to do my presentation.
所以我已经把我的想法记下来了，我要做我的演讲。
This is a promise I'm going to do my presentation.
这是我要做我的演讲的承诺。
One time I have not prepared this presentation before.
有一次我以前没有准备过这个演示文稿。
I have not given this presentation before.
我以前没有做过这个介绍。
This is real.
这是真的。
OK I might cut little pieces to make it shorter.
好的，我可能会切小块以使其更短。
If if I need to just to save you some time watching but I'm only going to do this presentation one time
如果我需要只是为了节省您观看的时间，但我只会做一次这个演示
I want it to come across as natural I want it to be natural because I want to show you that you can
我希望它看起来很自然 我希望它自然，因为我想向你展示你可以
make an outline and then do the presentation five minutes later it's not a big deal.
做一个大纲，然后在五分钟后做演示，这没什么大不了的。
People get this big idea about well I got to work on my presentation for weeks and I guess if you have
人们对我有一个很好的想法
to prepare all of the slides and pictures in your PPE that's true.
准备好 PPE 中的所有幻灯片和图片真的。
But the basic ideas in your presentation you can get down in a simple outline and you could give the
但是你的演示文稿中的基本想法，你可以用一个简单的大纲来概括，你可以给出
outline without a PBT with very few minutes of planning.
没有 PBT 的大纲，只需几分钟的计划。
We've done this in just about I don't know how many minutes 10 10 minutes.
我们在不知道多少分钟 10 到 10 分钟内完成了这项工作。
Right.
正确的。
So it's actually not a big deal.
所以其实也没什么大不了的。
Here we go.
开始了。